# Kevin Daniel Mendoza Hernández

Computer Science Engineer

**★** English (Proficient), Spanish (Native)

■ kevin\_mendoza092@hotmail.com

() /benevos

★ https://benevos.vercel.app/

Tamaulipas, Mexico

**(**+52) 831 102 4666

## SUMMARY

Computer systems engineer with experience in full-stack solutions for projects involving web, mobile, server, and process automation technologies. I am a self-confident person who enjoys presenting ideas while learning from others, unafraid of public speaking or defending positions, and competent in fields such as public speaking, leadership, and interpersonal relationships. Despite all this, I am aware that I do not have all the knowledge in the world, but as an engineer, I believe that not knowing something doesn't mean it can't be learned. My favorite hobbies are video games, going to the gym, watching series, and learning new technologies and programming methods.

#### EXPERIENCE

## IT Auditor (February 2024 – June 2024)

INE (Mexican National Electoral Institute)

- Provision of IT auditing and consulting services
- Generation of documents with technical and executive information
- Conducted verification tests of infrastructure configurations
- Participation in the design and implementation of fault recovery tests
- System performance monitoring through Python

## Computer Science Engineer (January 2024 - April 2024)

Xelhua - CINVESTAV

- Resolution of backend issues related to elasticity in distributed systems to recover inactive containers in Docker
- Automation of fault detection with Python.
- Administration and manipulation of Linux-based servers with high data volumes.

## Fullstack Engineer (January 2024 – October 2023)

Calcula UAT - UAT

- Development of cross-platform applications
- Design, development, and implementation of a mobile application with Flutter
- Creation of a website using Next.js and Google Cloud Services with Firebase to create real-time cloud solutions
- Application of persistence techniques to maintain operations without Internet services available

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

# • Third Place | State's Final | English in My School (2019) by Conalep

- Contestant | Science and Engineering Fair (FECIT, 2023) by COTACYT
- Contestant | TAMCODER programming contest (2023) by CINVESTAV
- Contestant | TAMCODER programming contest (2022) by CINVESTAV
- Contestant | 17th ANIEI NATIONAL PROGRAMMING COMPETITION (2022)
- **Project's English translator** | Entrepreneurs Project (2018) by Conalep

#### EDUCATION

### **Computer Science Engineer**

Autonomous University of Tamaulipas (UAT)

#### **Computer Science Technician**

National College of Technical Vocational Education (CONALEP)

$\sim$			т				$\sim$	٨	т	C
U	С.	к	Т	H	_	ı۷	، ب	н	- 1	O

# SKILLS

 $\textbf{Google Cloud Computing} \; (\texttt{Coursing})$ 

Google - INROADS Mexico

**EF SET English Certificate** 

C2 (80/100) Proficient

Next.js React Redux Tailwind SASS Typescript Python Flutter MongoDB Firebase MySQL R. Native Docker

Linux Git GitHub HTML CSS Javascript